<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>aparcar</title><link>https://aparcar.org/</link><description>Recent content on aparcar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020, Paul Spooren.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aparcar.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LoRaWAN Evaluation</title><link>https://aparcar.org/lorawan-evaluation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aparcar.org/lorawan-evaluation/</guid><description>Introduction This project evaluates the LoRa frequency modulation and the LoRaWAN stack as an alternative for existing sensor setups using the technologies ZigBee and GSM. The current scope is to build a simple stack to collect sensor data and visualize them inside a web interface.
Within this work modular nodes were designed allowing to measure a variety of environmental metrics, including temperature, rain fall, humidity and sea level.
Software and hardware used on sensor nodes are documented to allow easy replication of the setup.</description></item><item><title>Live rain fall monitoring via LoRaWAN</title><link>https://aparcar.org/live-rain-fall-monitoring-via-lorawan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 18:54:11 -1000</pubDate><guid>https://aparcar.org/live-rain-fall-monitoring-via-lorawan/</guid><description>This text briefly describes a rain gauge setup which uses LoRaWAN to transmit rain fall events to an online database. The setup makes use of the high precision ONSET HOBO rain gauge. Instead of using the vendors data logger which requires manual at-device data transfers, a LoRaWAN compatible microcontroller sends data wirelessly.
LoRaWAN allows low bandwidth data transmissions over long ranges while requiring minimal power. While sensor nodes are individually managed, the gateways, receiving and forwarding data packets to an online database, can be maintained by institutions and are often free of charge.</description></item><item><title>Running OpenWrt with SELinux</title><link>https://aparcar.org/running-openwrt-with-selinux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 11:04:01 -1000</pubDate><guid>https://aparcar.org/running-openwrt-with-selinux/</guid><description>This blog post describes the creation and testing of OpenWrt images running SELinux to improve security. The support is still limited and not ready for any productive usage, however this post should give a basic idea of its current state.
History Back in November 2019 Thomas Petazzoni sent a first patchset adding optional SELinux support to OpenWrt. Due to the complexity of integrating SELinux into the OpenWrt build system and missing bits in the patchset, the patches never made it into the main branch.</description></item></channel></rss>